<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Erika Donovan</title>
    <description>Photographer. Front-End Developer. Crocheter.</description>
    <link>http://erikadonovan.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://erikadonovan.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Hmmm... I&#39;m a Front-End Dev?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Thursday night, around 9pm, we wrapped up the last class in the Part-Time HTML &amp;amp; CSS fall program and with that I’m officially a Front-End Developer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This coming week we have two evenings of program help and to ask any other questions we might have. Then we have demo day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m working hard on finishing my last project (and compiling questions) for Tuesday’s help session. I’m also working on finishing the holiday card for where I work, which I am super excited about being asked to build!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since September I’ve been spending two nights a week learning to code and another three actually trying to code and build websites and random index page files, testing out different ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve lost hours of reading and hours of painting or crocheting or drawing, but I couldn’t be happier spending that time in front of a computer screen stringing letters and characters together to form skillfully laid out grids of information. I love when I break my site and have to figure out what happened (usually I’m missing a closing div tag). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy. I’m so happy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://erikadonovan.com/Front-End-Dev/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://erikadonovan.com/Front-End-Dev/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Friday’s We Demo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week we were given our first HackerYou class projects. I jumped at the idea of coding my very own one page website from scratch! Which I haven’t done in over 10 years. On Friday afternoon we had a work demo. Three of us had side projects we were working on that we wanted to share, and I showed them what I had made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Well two of us did and one just wanted to demo how to use a beer funnel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I put my newly designed (following the list of items we needed to include) website up on the big screen for my co-workers, above, and then talked about it, showing what different things were and what I had learned in the first few weeks. I think they were impressed with it… or they are just really nice people that don’t want to put me down?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways! I had a lot of fun building the basic one page site on my own. I asked our front end dev to not help me with it, but he did help me figure one thing out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday, I woke up with the thought of redoing it to make it so much better (and not about pluto). I figured just showing what I could do was great but why not make it look good too? And so that’s how I spent my Saturday morning; with a cup of coffee, my cat (DJ Frankie Fresh), and my laptop redesigning my project and submitted my work. And then I kept making changes to it… and then more…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view my project here (please note it is not mobile friendly yet), it will (might) be changing over time and one day will hopefully become my actual website that I coded all on my own! (not a copied one from a friend).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://erikadonovan.com/fridays-we-demo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://erikadonovan.com/fridays-we-demo/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yesterday I called myself a Dev!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;tonight-completes-the-fourth-week-of-my-part-time-coding-program-with-hackeryou-on-web-development&quot;&gt;Tonight completes the fourth week of my part-time coding program with HackerYou on Web Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first learned what HTML was in grade 10 when I wanted to see how websites where built. So one day I got a book on it and I started building very basic, poorly designed, frame based websites for my friend’s sport teams and fan pages for celebrities I was a fan of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And then one day I just stopped.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never wanted to work in tech growing up. I had always been great with computers and was able to learn software quickly, but I had a set back that same year. In grade 10, I took the Intro to Drafting class in high school. I was in love with architecture and buildings and how you could use a computer to draw plans. What ended up happening, a side from me learning AutoCAD, as I was the only girl in a class of 11, where the computer pods each held five students. Hence, I sat alone. Every day. I was consistently reminded by the other students that it was not a place for me or for other girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My teacher was amazing though. I finished the course workload in the first three weeks, this is what happens when focus meets “no one wants to talk to you”. So, he got the school to give me access to Adobe Flash and Photoshop and I taught myself how to use them. When the class ended I had the highest mark in the class, even though I failed to complete the final independent project. I had also been asked to do my grade 11 co-op with GM, which I turned down upon hearing all my co-workers would be male (my mom still regrets this decision, I do not).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went on to take a few business computer classes in grade 11 and 12, I was apart of the editing crew on the News Team, and in college I pretty much did everyone else’s website project in Year 3 Computers (I was studying Sport Management).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But! Now I work in the tech industry, and although I am not on the dev team and the closet I come to working with code is helping my customers figure out code issues on their websites, I wanted to re-learn HTML and CSS. And now I am!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two nights a week I walk from work over to The Lab on Queen St W and I learn to code for two hours with other students, one teacher, and two+ awesome mentors that help us when we are confused. And it’s two nights a week that I am enjoying and happy to be extending my “in front of the computer” hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be taking the Web Development course until mid-December and by then I should have a well rounded understanding of HTML5, CSS3, and responsive design! And yesterday!, while one of my co-workers (a real dev) was showing me what something meant a few others where talking (loudly!) and I asked them to shhh because the devs where working, including me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://erikadonovan.com/called-myself-a-dev/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://erikadonovan.com/called-myself-a-dev/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>